《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我们把超光速计算机与导航 检修组、消防组的计算机联网
We network the FTL computer with the Nav, DC and fire control computers.
一旦连上  我们仅需10分钟来完成计算
Once they're linked, we'll only need 10 minutes to complete the calculations.
真的?你在软件方面比赛昂人棋高一招吗?
Really? You're going to outthink the Cylons at computer software?
赛昂人正在攻击我方网络
Cylons are hacking our network.
企图进入主机
Attempting to access our mainframe.
怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
是病毒 长官  我想它一定
It's the virus, sir. I think it must have spawned copies
繁殖到其他的计算机系统了
of itself in some of the computer systems.
病毒阻断了主电力和辅助单元
It's knocked out main power and auxiliary units.
我爱你  上士
I love you, Chief.
你想我怎么样  西洛?
What do you want from me, Helo?
她是赛昂人!
She's a Cylon.
我不会让你杀了她
I'm not going to let you kill her, okay.
她怀着我的孩子!
She's carrying my child.
我有晚期乳腺癌
I have terminal breast cancer.
卡托医生会证实诊断结果
Dr. Cottle will verify the diagnosis.
我只能活几个月了
I have a few months to live.
蝮蛇战机5-4-2-8-9号
Five-four-two-eight-niner.
今天感觉怎么样?
So, how are we feeling today?
哦  糟糕透了!
Great!
嗨  我就知道你在这儿
HELO: Thought I'd find you here.
我是卡尔·阿格森
Karl Agathon.
想参加吗?
You wanna sit in?
还是下次吧
Maybe next time.
他就是那个赛昂的情人
So, he's the Cylon lover?
你懂什么?我才不在乎他跟谁好上
You know what? I don't care who or what he fraks.
他救过我的小命  知道吧?
He saved my ass down there, all right?
可是人怎么会和塞鬼子谈恋爱呢?
How could anyone fall in love with a toaster, though?
在我们的莎伦向老头子开那两枪之前
Same way I hear everyone was high-fiving our Sharon
每个人对她评价都很高
right before she put two in Adama's chest.
这些混蛋能让你神魂颠倒
The bastards frak with your head.
是啊  看看上士就知道了
Yeah. Just ask the Chief.
我早就知道!
I knew it.
我得喝上一杯
I need a drink.
瞧你:晒黑了  休息好了  精神焕发
Tanned, rested and ready! Look at you.
当然休息好了  在牢房里除了吃就是睡
Rested, anyway. Nothing to do but eat and sleep in the can.
"未经许可开火"?多么蹩脚的指控啊
"Unauthorized discharge of a firearm. " What a bogus charge.
他们应该给你发一枚奖章   表彰你轰掉那个面包炉
They should have given you a medal for popping that toaster.
上士  我听说你为我求情
Chief, I heard that you went to bat for me.
别提了
Forget it.
我希望你知道......    别提了
I just want you to know... Forget it.
我需要每一个笨蛋下属
I need all the knuckle draggers I can get.
莎伦曾驾驶它飞行了47次
TYROL: Sharon flew 47 missions in this thing and
仍然不能顺利降落
still couldn't trap a landing worth a damn.
每次都会撞弯起落架
Had to bend her undercarriage back into place after every landing.
近接使她很紧张
Approaches made her nervous.
她害怕你注视着她
She was afraid you'd be watching.
我一直那样注视
I usually was.
不打了
Screw it.
你留着这么多好牌干啥?
You're folding with three up?
你疯了?
Are you crazy?
你来揍我啊  红桃J  对吧?
Not when you've got me beat. Prince high red, right?
打牌这么久了  我懂得收牌
Been playing with these cards for so long, I know every fold.
人生难得事事如意
So, life's a bitch.
你想哭没人拦你
What do you want to do, cry about it?
不  我只想结束  行了吧?
No, I just want it to end, okay?
糟糕的食物  无休止的换班
The bad food, the endless rotations,
假装打牌是一天最快乐的时候
pretending that a card game is the high point of our day!
这不会持续很久对吧?
It's not going to last forever, all right.
离地球已经不远了
Earth is out there.
对啊
Right.
我们或许都在...
We could all be chasing our tails over some
自欺欺人
half-assed planetarium show.
你们都见鬼吧!
You guys can all go to hell.
我去找西洛
I'm gonna go find Helo.
好主意  说不定那个赛昂婊子教给他些新花样呢
Good idea. Maybe that Cylon whore taught him a few tricks.
上士
Look, Chief.
我从没打算和莎伦......
I never intended for Sharon to know that.
你知道  自然而然就发生了
You know, it just kind of evolved.
只是一对苦命鸳鸯  嗯?
Just a couple of lovesick kids, huh?
我知道她对你的感觉
I know how she felt about you. Okay?
她一直爱着你
She loved you.
她告诉你她接下去的计划了吗?
Did she fill you in on the rest of the plan?
我和她服完役后就退伍
She and I were going to muster out at the end of our service.
我们会结婚
You know? That we would get married,
或许还会要小孩
maybe we would have children.
我猜我真是个大猪头  对吧?
I guess I'm just a big frakking idiot, though, huh?
或许他妈的面包炉都计划好了
Probably that godsdamn toaster's plan all along.
别那么说她
Don't call her that. To sucker some moron
骗一个笨蛋来跟她一起生小孩
into giving her a kid.
你知道吗?或许我该感激你
But you know what? I should probably be grateful to you.
为什么?
Probably be grateful. You know why?
因为 她肚子里的那个怪物可能是我的!
Because that freak in her belly could've been mine.
你没事儿吧?真对不起!
Hey. You okay? Sorry.
你这个浑......
Son of a bitch!
够了  上士!
That's enough, Chief.
轮不到你说话!
You don't get to call it.
够了!
Enough!
来啊  你这个面包炉的情人!
Come on, you damn toaster lover!
我都不知道为什么我要生你的气
I don't even know why I'm mad at you.
我的莎伦死了
My Sharon's dead.
那个被关起来的东西
That thing in the brig,
根本就不是莎伦
that isn't Sharon.
收到  蓝色领队  报告燃料状况
Roger, Blue leader. Say fuel state.
他妈的怎么回事?
What the hell is that?
长官  是我们的问题  我找不到信号源
It was us, sir. But I can't find the source of the transmission.
什么东西触发了我们的通讯系统   自动广播信号
Something's triggering our comm system to broadcast an automatic signal.
赛昂人可以通过这个信号跟踪锁定我们的位置
Which the Cylons could trace to get a fix on our position.
只是暂时的
Let's assume that for now.
更新和传送紧急跳跃位置
Update and distribute emergency jump sites,
以防他们再次出现
just in case they show up again.
小杜  告诉我......
Dee, get me a...
我没事儿  长官    别动
I'm okay, sir. No. No, stay down.
我们马上送你去卡托医生那儿  确保你没事儿
We'll get you to Doc Cottle to make sure everything's okay.
盖塔先生  查清楚
Mr. Gaeta, find out what happened.
我没事儿
I'm okay.
盖塔先生
Mr. Gaeta?
一个电涌冲击了仪表板
A power surge energized the board.
自从赛昂人渗入我们的网络
System's been twitchy ever since
系统一直不稳定
the Cylons infiltrated our network.
盖塔先生  这决不是小故障
Mr. Gaeta, this is more than a twitch.
指挥官说的对
The commander's right.
即使你得一条一条地检查程序
I don't care if you have to go through this program line by line.
也得修好它!
Fix it.
什么?
Excuse me?
你听见我说的了
You heard me.
长官  我正在运行我们所有的诊断程序
Sir, I'm running every diagnostic we've got.
逐行检查代码可能花费数天
Checking each line of code could take days.
我对借口不感兴趣  修好它!
I am not interested in excuses. Fix it.
这不是借口  这是他妈的事实!
It's not an excuse, sir. It's a frakking fact!
盖塔先生
Mr. Gaeta.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
要和大家齐心协力
Pull yourself together.
对不起  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
他到底搞什么名堂?
What the hell is his problem?
接连几个月的无休止工作
Months on the run and what do we have to show for it?
可我们只有人员伤亡  情况不断恶化
Casualties. Deteriorating conditions.
这些人员需要休养
This crew needs a rest.
否则他们终究会垮的 索尔
It's finally hitting them, Saul.
我们的老命都会玩儿完
Our old lives are gone.
我们唯一能够期待的就是他们
The only thing we have to look forward to is this.
上士  289号蝮蛇战机在哪儿?
Chief, where's 2-8-niner?
我今天要用它训练
I need her for drills today.
长官  它飞不了
She was grounded, sir.
什么?得多久?
What? For how long?
永远
Permanently.
我们竭尽所能  可它还是报废了
We're salvaging what we can, but it's gone.
见鬼!我要那艘船飞起来
Damn it, I need that ship online.
上尉  我能说什么?  引擎座被击中了
What can I tell you, Captain? Engine mounts are shot,
驾驶舱的密封破了
cockpit seals are cracked.
如果这是一匹马  我宁愿开枪打死它    上士  有情况
If it was a horse, they'd shoot it. Got something, Chief.
上士  跟我一起干吧  我需要你的帮助
APOLLO: Chief, come on. Work with me here. I need your help.
你要我怎么样?把我的人累死?
What do you want me to do? Work my crew to death?
不  尽力就行
No. Just do your best.
没人盼望出现奇迹
Nobody's expecting any miracles.
或许这就是问题所在
Maybe that's the problem.
妈的  为什么不试试
TYROL: Frak it, why not?
上士  干嘛呢?
What's going on, Chief?
好  听着
All right, here's the deal.
我们来建一艘新的战斗机
We are going to build a new fighter.
那其它的飞机怎么办?
What about the rest of the ships?
我堆着三天的维修没做完呢
I'm three days backlogged on repairs as is.
这完全是业余工作
This is strictly an off-duty project.
不能影响正常维修
Nobody takes one minute away from regular maintenance and repairs.
明白吗?
You got it?
你觉得我们不行吗?
You don't think we can do this?
我都不知如何着手
I wouldn't even know how to begin.
你要知道就怪了    去你的
What else is new? Screw you.
他要装配骨架
Okay. He's talking about fabricating a frame,
航空控制系统  维生系统
avionics, life support.
这简直就不可能
It's frakking impossible.
知道么?算了  我不需要你
You know what, then? Forget you. I don't need you.
等一下  上士  别这样
Chief, wait. It's not like that.
我说行了  回去工作
I said forget it. Get back to work.
这是命令
That's an order.
我还能活多久?
How much time do I have?
几个星期  最多一个月
Weeks. A month at the outside.
我可以工作吗?
Will I be able to work?
可以  除非癌症扩散到大脑
Unless the cancer goes to your brain.
如果那样  你就......
If that happens...
某人有点偏激
Someone's a tad aggressive.
闭嘴  开你的枪
Just shut up and shoot.
跟你或者雷斯克说话
My gods, between you and Racetrack, it's like...
都像老虎屁股拔毛
Having a conversation is like walking through a minefield.
你最没资格谴责我的态度
And you're the last person who should be lecturing me about manners.
我听说你欺负蒂罗尔上士
From what I hear, you've also been riding Chief Tyrol pretty good.
按下那个按钮
Press it.
我只提醒他  维护我的飞机
I just reminded him that I expect Viper maintenance
要比他的业余爱好重要
to take precedence over his hobby project.
是--啊!
STARBUCK: Nice.
我很奇怪他没给你一拳头
I'm surprised he didn't take a swing at you.
行了  星芭儿
Come on, Starbuck.
你不会真的觉得那个破烂还能飞上天吧?
You don't actually think that piece of junk's gonna actually fly, do you?
50块  赌它能飞
50 cubits says he gets it in the air.
啊?谁来驾驶?
Yeah? And who's gonna fly it?
我才不呢
It's not gonna be me.
别指望我
Don't look at me!
不指望你
APOLLO: I wasn't looking at you.
怎么了?
What?
我来飞
I'll fly it.
你?
You?
我
Me.
为什么?
Why?
因为......当别人都只会站在一边抱怨......
Because while everyone else is standing around whining...
我们抱怨?
APOLLO: We're whining?
上士正积极工作
...the Chief is doing something positive.
我很感动  真的
I'm deeply moved. Really?
说实话 是的
Honestly, I am.
他嘴巴发青了
His lips are blue!
你看起来像个蓝莓!
You look like a blueberry.
氧气不足
There's no oxygen in here.
氧气不足    没氧气了
There's no oxygen in here. No oxygen.
我没子弹了
I'm out.
打得好
Nice shot.
环境系统当时显示
The environmental computer decided
射击房已经压力过高
that the firing range was over pressurized
于是开始放气补偿
and started bleeding out air to compensate.
如果再放气两分钟  我们就死定了
Two more minutes, we may have been dead.
能量波动  设备故障
Power fluctuations. Equipment failures.
长官  我想我找到原因了
Sir, I think I've found what's causing it.
是什么?    赛昂的逻辑炸弹
What is that? BALTAR: A Cylon logic bomb.
智慧型计算机病毒
A heuristic computer virus.
能够学习、进化
It's capable of learning, evolving.
可能现在正并发运行于
It's probably running in parallel
舰上每一台计算机
with every computer in the ship right now,
只等着被激活
just waiting to be activated.
现在都清楚了
No doubt left behind
您被枪击的那天
when the Cylons infiltrated the network Colonel Tigh set up
赛昂渗入了泰上校设立的网络
the day you were shot, sir.
那已经是几星期以前了
That was weeks ago.
为什么现在才发生?
Why now?
长官  很可能到现在
Most likely, sir, it took that long
他们才破解了我们的加密口令
for it to crack our encrypted pass-codes.
一旦成功  就开始...
And once that happened, it started testing
测试控制我们
its ability to control our systems.
电力和环境系统的能力
Electrical, environmental.
你如何解决它?
How do you kill it?
比较难办
Well, that's the tricky part.
赛昂病毒尤其难以根除
If it's a Cylon virus, it is extremely difficult to eradicate.
我猜我们很幸运
Well, I guess I'm pretty lucky then.
因为我们船上有个专家
Because I have an expert onboard.
叫西洛把这个给我们的犯人看看
Tell Helo to run this past our prisoner.
来啊  来啊
Come on. Come on.
混蛋
For frak's sakes.
妈的
Son of a bitch!
见鬼
Gods damn it!
我能行  快回去工作
I got it. Go back to work.
上士  这是两个人的活儿
It's a two-man job, Chief.
你想不想装上这个机翼?
You want this wing up or not?
我数到三:一  二  三
On three. One, two, three.
好极了  好极了  别动  拉那边
TYROL: Great. Great, hold it there. Pull it that way.
长官  全船正持续遭受电力浪涌...
Sir, we're continuing to experience power spikes
和设备故障
and equipment failures across the ship.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们最好提高警戒等级
We'd better up our alert status and put
叫检修组待命
our damage control teams on standby.
还不到时候
Not yet.
你看了上士在造的那架战机吗?
Have you seen the ship that the Chief is building?
他的空中楼阁?我不用看
His imaginary fighter? I don't need to see it.
就知道他是在浪费时间
I know it's a waste of time.
甲板上的人们可不这么想
The deck crew doesn't seem to think so.
我们应该关心的是我们剩下的舰队
We need to focus on the fleet we've got left,
而不是陷入白日梦
not get bogged down in some pipe dream.
我们应该叫停他们
You should shut it down.
有可能
It may come to that.
不过这件事给了他们目标
This project, it's giving them something.
我不会夺走它的  除非万不得已
I'm not going to take that away until I have to.
卡托医生说我没事了  只是撞了一下
Doc Cottle cleared me. And I feel like hitting something.
对  不要僵硬  不要僵硬
Okay. Don't square up.
转体  屈膝
Rotate, and just drop the knee.
不错
That's nice.
如果要摔倒对手
Now, if you want to throw them,
我来示范
I'll be you.
勒住脖子  抓住手腕  固定胳膊
Head in a lock, grab the wrist, secure the arm
跪下去  转体45度
and I'm just gonna drop the knee, rotate 45.
好
Okay.
你没事儿吧?    嗯
Are you all right? Yeah.
就像基本训练一样
Just like we did in basic.
我们实际演练一下
Let's bring a live opponent into the mix.
别忘了夺走刀子
MAN: Nice. And strip the knife.
比利!
DUALLA: Billy.
嗨
Hey. Hey.
你来舰上多久了?    我刚到
How long have you been onboard? I just arrived.
你还有赛昂人进攻前
HELO: Do you have actual memories of being
和上士在一起的记忆吗?
with the Chief before the Cylon attack?
有
Yeah.
我真的很对不起你  你问过的
I'm sorry. You asked.
你还爱着他吗?
Do you still love him?
西洛
Helo,
你是我孩子的父亲
you're the father of my child.
在我心里是第一位的 无人可以替代
You're the first in my heart and nothing is ever going to change that.
好吧  说说这个
All right. We have to get to this.
波塔尔博士说这是一种赛昂人的逻辑炸弹
Dr. Baltar says it's some sort of Cylon logic bomb.
你能看出什么来吗?
Do you see anything?
倒过来
Can you flip?
莎伦?
Sharon?
莎伦
Sharon.
我得跟阿达玛指挥官谈谈 马上!
I need to talk to Commander Adama. Right now.
怎么了?
Why?
是的  这是赛昂病毒  它已经开始了解你们的系统
It's a Cylon virus, all right. It's been learning your systems.
试探  适应  发现弱点
Testing, adapting, finding weak spots.
目的是什么?
For what?
这样他们就可以用卡拉狄加的系统来对付你们
So they can turn Galactica's systems against you.
把你们撞向其他船  引爆军火库
Crash you into other ships, detonate your weapons stores,
闷死船员
suffocate the crew.
那你和孩子会怎样?
What about you? The baby?
我只是他们微不足道的
I'm a liability to them,
失误
a mistake.
西洛  这个逻辑炸弹要进化几个小时
Helo, this logic bomb will run its course in a matter of hours.
一旦完成  赛昂将凌驾于我们
Once it does, the Cylons will be on top of us.
他们会把我们赶尽杀绝
They're going to kill us all.
阿达玛指挥官--    请简短截说
Commander Adama... Whatever it is you have to say, make it quick.
嗯  我本不想这么说  可是你让驾驶舱太靠后了
Well, I hate to say it, but you've got the cockpit too far back.
机动飞行时会有重心问题
You're gonna run into CG problems when you maneuver.
上尉  我们不会机动飞行
We're not going for maneuverability, Captain.
我们只要速度
We're going for speed.
此外  反正你不指望这东西能飞起来
Besides, you didn't think this thing would fly anyway.
驾驶舱这么装  肯定飞不起来
Well, it sure as hell won't with the cockpit rammed up its...
小杜!
Dee?
啊?
Hey!
你在这里干什么?
APOLLO: What are you doing here?
弄通讯系统
Communications, I think.
上士对流体力学很在行   可通讯系统却是一团糟
She's great with hydraulics, but this comm system is a mess.
那还用说
Ten-hut.
不看不知道
I had to see this with my own eyes.
一下子整个作战情报中心的人都跑下来了
Won't be long before we have the whole CIC down here.
阿波罗  你也在忙这个任务吗?
You working on this class project, too, Apollo?
不  长官
No.
看到还有人有一点点理智  真是太好了
It's good to see someone has a little sense.
上士在哪儿?器械室?
Where's the Chief? Tool room?
长官  他去休息一下
Aye, getting some rack time, sir.
上士  这是什么?
TIGH: What's this, Chief?
长官  我在配清洗零件的溶剂
Making solvent, sir. To clean engine parts.
清洗你个头
Solvent, my ass.
我的鼻子告诉我你在造酒!
I know a still when I smell it,
你到底在干什么?
what the hell are you up to?
我需要用酒来换些零件
I need booze to trade for parts.
我在舰队到处搜罗
I'm scrounging most of what I can from the fleet.
还没找到引擎
But I need engines.
得有阿达玛指挥官的许可
I know I need Commander Adama's
我才能从报废的船上拆零件
permission to cannibalize one of the wrecks.
不管有没有引擎   我们都知道那块垃圾不可能飞起来
Engines or not, we both know that piece of crap out there is never going to fly.
上校  我得试试
I gotta try, Colonel.
为什么?
What's the point?
因为我只剩下那艘船和我的职责
Because that ship, the work, that's all I've got left.
别的我什么都没有......
I don't have that, I...
我差点忘了  我答应巴帕卡的副官
I almost forgot. I promised the XO
要帮他一个忙
of the Baah Pakal I'd help him out.
长官?
Sir?
有些废的DDG-62引擎
He's got some obsolete DDG-62 engines
正占据着他的飞行甲板呢
that's taking up space on his flight deck.
我告诉过他
They're probably crap but I told him
我会尽快派些人去拖走这些垃圾
that I would have a crew in there to haul them out as soon as possible.
很高兴能帮上忙  长官!
Glad to be of help, sir.
好极了
Good.
总统女士  您的飞船正在待命
Madam President, your shuttle's ready.
好的
Of course.
再次感谢您允许我使用您的寝室
Thank you again for letting me use your quarters.
不客气
Please.
我希望把这个还给您
I wanted to return this.
这是件礼物
This was a gift.
您说过"书从不外借"
"Never lend a book," I know.
我已经占有它太久了
But I've had it far too long.
它属于您的收藏
It belongs in your collection.
我快赶不上开会了
I'm late for a quorum meeting.
出什么问题了?
Is there a problem?
我们的计算机已被赛昂病毒感染
Our computers have been infected by a Cylon virus
影响到全舰的所有系统
corrupting systems throughout the entire ship.
刚刚得知这只是
I've just been notified that this is a prelude
赛昂人全面进攻的前奏
to an all-out attack by the Cylons.
我想你已经设法解决了
I assume you've tried to disable it.
盖塔先生和副总统正在处理
Mr. Gaeta and the Vice President are handling that right now.
没什么希望
I'm not hopeful.
指挥官  我只能在...
Commander, I'm not sure what I can offer you here
精神上支持你
besides my moral support.
总统女士
Actually, Madam President,
您有什么建议吗?
I could use your advice.
你想怎么做?
You want to what?
完全清空我们的计算机驱动器
Completely erase our computer drives,
冷启动全舰系统
cold restart the entire ship's system
然后用我们的战前备份恢复系统
and then restore them using our prewar backups.
让我们光着屁股直到系统重新工作?
Leaving us with our pants down until we're back online.
指挥官不会答应的
The Commander will never go for this.
长官  其实我已经跟他谈过了
I've already spoken to him, sir.
他怎么说?    他正在考虑
What did he say? He's considering it.
这是唯一清除病毒的方法
It's the only way to destroy the virus.
我记得指挥官让你别插手这一块
I thought the Commander told you to stay out of this.
我很抱歉  可您究竟愿不愿意躲过这一劫
I'm sorry, do you want to survive this one or not?
好吧  那我们计算一次跳跃
All right, so we calculate a jump and
离那些赛昂混蛋远远的
get some distance on these Cylon bastards...
不行  长官  我们不能冒这个险
No, sir, we can't risk a jump.
包括导航在内的所有系统都不安全
All of our systems are compromised, including navigation.
病毒可能会把我们扔在一颗恒星的正中间
The virus could drop us in the middle of a sun.
我们快没时间了
We're running out of time.
我们的信号即将到达赛昂舰队
Our signal's gonna catch up with the Cylon fleet.
如果还没有任何进展......
If we haven't come up with anything before then...
他们就会控制我们整个系统
They'll take control of all of our systems
我们只能任人宰割
and then they'll have a hundred ways to kill us.
我刚从我们的赛昂犯人那儿来
I've just come from seeing our Cylon prisoner.
她可能有解决办法
She's offering a possible solution to the problem.
你在考虑能否信任她
And you're wondering if you can trust her.
我尽量控制自己
It took everything I have
才没有去掐死她
not to put my hands around her throat.
不敢相信我会有这种企图
I can't believe I'm contemplating this.
我们都知道赛昂人善于操纵思想
We both know the Cylons are experts at manipulation.
混淆是非
They will do anything to confuse you.
可并不是她开枪打我
This is not the one who shot me.
他们之间会有天壤之别吗?
Can they really be that different from one another?
指挥官  如果你问我
Commander, if you're asking me
你的判断是否受到
if it's possible that your judgment's been clouded,
你与这个型号的赛昂人相处的影响
by your history with this particular Cylon model,
我会说是
I'd have to say yes.
不过
But
我们创造了他们
we created them.
我们总会找到共同点的
There's always a chance we might find common ground.
我们得动作快点
We need to work quickly.
时间已经不够了
We're on borrowed time.
放开她
Let her go.
是 长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
小杜  你还带着你父亲的小刀吗?
Dee, do you still carry your father's pocketknife?
给她
Give it to her.
盖塔先生  请帮我建立光纤通讯连接
Mr. Gaeta, can you set me up with a fiber-optic comm link?
我要向所有频率广播
I need broadcast to all frequencies
并且直接联入主机
and direct contact to the mainframe.
照办!    是
ADAMA: Do it. GAETA: Sir.
这儿  莎伦
Right here, Sharon.
谢谢
Thanks.
多架赛昂战机来袭
GAETA: Dradis. Here they come. Multiple targets.
方位371-552
Bearing 371 carom 552. Cylon raiders.
这些混蛋追踪到了我们
Bastards tracked us, all right.
蝮蛇战机出击
Launch Vipers.
阿波罗  突袭机保持队形
MAN ON RADIO: Apollo, the raiders are holding.
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗
APOLLO: Galactica, Apollo.
赛昂突袭机保持队形
Raiders are holding formation.
重复  赛昂突袭机保持队形
Repeat, raiders are holding formation.
见鬼了!
What the hell?
他们的步骤是
BOOMER: Okay, this is how it's going to work.
赛昂突袭机发出指令  激活病毒
The raiders are going to send a signal to activate the virus.
这得好几秒钟
It could take a few seconds.
听我的口令  初始化删除程序
On my mark, initiate the computer wipe.
错过时机了......
Miss the window...
病毒接管了舰上所有系统
The virus takes over every system in the ship.
有时你只能孤注一掷   对吗  指挥官?
Sometimes you gotta roll the hard six. Right, Commander?
她在干什么?
What the hell is she doing?
长官  莎伦和赛昂人联系上了
DUALLA: They've made contact, sir.
速度太快  我跟不上
GAETA: It's moving too fast, I can't follow it.
我们得停下来
We gotta stop this.
准备  听我的命令  执行系统删除
Stand by to execute computer wipe on my command.
系统准备就绪
System is ready, sir.
现在清除硬盘!
Wipe the hard drives now.
动手吧!
Do it.
我的天  搞什么飞机!
STARBUCK: My gods, what are they doing?
火力系统离线  雷达无效  系统崩溃
Weapons are still offline. No dradis. Systems down.
我们面临一场大屠杀!
We're looking at a godsdamn bloodbath.
毫无防卫!
We're defenseless.
阿波罗  热狗  他们来了!
HOTDOG: Apollo, Hotdog. Here they come!
收到  热狗
All right, copy, Hotdog.
我的天哪!一定有几百艘!
Gods, there must be hundreds of them.
赛昂人还在逼近  她耍了我们!
Cylons are still moving in. She set us up!
把枪给我
Give me your sidearm.
是 长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
如果他们是来找你的  他们会非常失望
If they're coming for you, they're gonna be very disappointed.
开枪!
Do it.
你还在等什么?
TIGH: What are you waiting for?
等这个!
This.
怎么回事?
What the hell?
我们刚发射了一个信号
We just transmitted a signal.
呃  卡拉狄加?  他们好像失去了动力
Galactica? They seem to have lost power.
漫无目的四处漂浮
They're drifting out of control!
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
赛昂人发个病毒给我们
Cylons sent a computer virus.
我们回信问候他们
But we just sent one back.
阿波罗  这是卡拉狄加  好好回敬一下他们!
Apollo, this is Galactica. Kill the bastards.
来吧宝贝儿!
STARBUCK: Yeah! Come on, baby.
收到  同志们  开火!
Roger that. Vipers, weapons free.
冲啊!
Engage.
出来混  总是要"还"的!
This is payback.
喜欢吗?
Yeah! How do you like that?
看我的!
You seeing this?
让面包炉见鬼去吧!
APOLLO: Got this toaster padlocked.
来吧
Come on!
一箭双雕!
I got another where that one came from!
伙计们  一个不留!冲啊!
STARBUCK: Guys, clean them up. Come on, let's go.
来人!    是 长官
Officers. GUARD: Yes, sir.
把这个东西带回牢房
Take this thing back to its cell.
这样就行了  上士
There you go, Chief.
小个子真灵活
Nice to be small, huh?
还有几个引擎 过去看看
Ship's got more than one engine. Get to it.
快完工了
We are so damn close.
得铺上些金属
There has got to be some extra metal lying
还得加些...
around that we can use to skin this thing.
板材舱壁之类
Floorboards, extra bulkheads, something.
基本上都以维修蝮蛇战机的名义预订了
Most of it's ticketed for Viper repair.
谁说一定得用金属包裹机身?
HELO: Who says you need metal?
合成碳    你的主意真棒  西洛
Carbon composite. STARBUCK: Good call, Helo.
它在雷达上几乎隐形
It's gonna be hard as hell to see on dradis
可问题是  它飞得起来吗?
but the question is, will it fly?
看着吧!
Just watch me.
设备正常
STARBUCK: Instruments: in the green.
燃料压力正常
Fuel pressure: nominal.
阿波罗  星芭儿
Apollo, Starbuck.
黑鸟飞行准备开始
Blackbird flight is cleared for launch.
预热引擎
Run-up.
磁力锁打开  开始发射程序
MAN ON RADIO: Maglock secure, initiate launch sequence.
你这家伙  可千万别炸死我!
Don't blow up on me, you bastard.
准许起飞
Clear for launch.
黑鸟飞起来了!
DUALLA: Blackbird is away.
放轻松点行吗?慢慢开始!
Will you take it easy? Start slow.
你是在测试飞机
You're testing the ship.
不是在炫耀技术!
It's not about the pilot showing off.
我可没炫耀
STARBUCK: Who's showing off?
见鬼  那这是干嘛
APOLLO: Gods damn it, what is this?
那你想证明什么?
What are you trying to prove?
我什么都不想证明!
I'm not trying to prove anything.
不可思议!
You've got to be kidding me.
呜!
Oh, lords.
来见识一下我们的宝贝儿能干些什么
Okay. Let's see what this baby can do.
星芭儿  你在哪儿?
APOLLO: Starbuck, where are you?
星芭儿  你能收到吗?星芭儿!
Starbuck, do you hear me? Starbuck!
我没...     她不见了!
MAN: I'm not... APOLLO: She's gone!
卡拉狄加  这是阿波罗  我找不到她了
Galactica, Apollo. I've lost her.
我找不到她
I've lost her.
雷达也没有她的踪影
DUALLA: No dradis contact.
星芭儿  你在哪儿?
APOLLO: Starbuck, where are you?
星芭儿  请回答
Starbuck, come in.
星芭儿  能收到吗?
Starbuck, do you read?
卡拉  你没事儿吧?
Kara, are you okay?
你当然会和我失去联系!
Of course, you lost contact.
这本来就是隐形战斗机  忘了吗?
It's a damn stealth ship, remember?
啊!你--
Oh, you...
向指挥官敬礼!
OFFICER: Commander on deck.
稍息
As you were.
蒂罗尔上士
ROSLIN: Chief Tyrol?
这就是黑鸟?
This is the Blackbird?
是的  总统女士
Yes, ma'am.
您的光临使我很荣幸
Madam President, this is an honor.
不  是我的荣幸  简直太杰出了!
No, the honor's mine. It's remarkable.
只是一架战机而已
Just a ship, ma'am.
你太谦虚了 我们所经受的苦难
ROSLIN: You're much too modest. After what we've been through,
使我们绝望沮丧
it would be very easy to give up, to lose hope.
可不是此时 不是此地!
But not here. Not today.
这不仅仅是一架战机  上士
This is more than a ship, Chief.
这是信念的见证
This is an act of faith.
无论牺牲多么巨大
It is proof that despite all we've lost,
我们坚持着
we keep trying.
齐心协力  我们会挺过去的
And we will get through this, all of us, together.
我发誓!
I promise.
指挥官
Commander.
总统女士
Madam President,
这里还有个惊喜......
this was supposed to be a surprise,
不过...
but, well.
太谢谢你们了!
Thank you.
总统  为我们剪彩吧
If you'll do us the honors, Madam President.
没问题!
Of course.
好
Okay.
开个玩笑
Kidding.
采用复合碳真是个好主意
Hell of an idea, using carbon composites.
干得好!
MAN: It was a good job.
漂亮!
Nice work.
太温暖了
That was lovely.
他们是真心的
They wanted to do that for you.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
如果我们当初没有相信那个赛昂人
None of this would have been possible
也就不会有现在了
if you hadn't trusted the Cylon.
我采纳了您的建议  寻找共同点
I took your advice, met on common ground.
共同点是什么?
What was that?
我们都想活下去
We both wanted to live.